In Havana, music isn't a pastime, it's a way of life.
Buena Vista Social Club is a documentary, music film directed by Wim Wenders.
In this fascinating Oscar-nominated documentary, American guitarist Ry Cooder brings together a group of legendary
Cuban folk musicians (some in their 90s) to record a Grammy-winning CD in their native city of Havana.
The result is a spectacular compilation of concert footage from the group's gigs in Amsterdam and New York City's famed
Carnegie Hall, with director Wim Wenders capturing not only the music -- but also the musicians' life stories.
Self, played by Compay Segundo.
Self, played by Eliades Ochoa.
Self, played by Ry Cooder.
Self, played by Joachim Cooder.
Self, played by Ibrahim Ferrer.
Self, played by Omara Portuondo.
Buena Vista Social Club is a 1999 documentary film directed by Wim Wenders about the music of
Cuba, featuring the musicians who recorded the 1996 album Buena Vista Social Club.
The film is an international co-production of Germany, the
United States, the United Kingdom, France, and Cuba.
In 2020, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".